So the answer that I think is best is choice four.
我认为选项四是最佳答案
Choice two is pretty good.
选项二也很不错
But I think choice four is a little bit better.
但选项四更好些
Choice one and choice three would be really difficult.
选项一和三都太麻烦了
So let's look at how these look to see why choice four is the best choice.
那么我们来看看 为什么四是最佳选择
So I need to shrink the choices to have a little more room for drawing.
首先缩小这些选项 为我的图解省点空间
So here's what option one would look like.
这就是选项一
We have a single list
我们有一个列表
and the elements of the list are keywords.
列表的元素就是 关键词
Each keyword is a string and the keyword is followed by the URLs where that keyword appears.
每个关键词都是一个字符串 关键词后面则是出现该关键词的 URL
So for option one, we have a list, and it's a single list containing strings.
所以 选项一里 我们有一个列表 这个列表包含了字符串
Each string is either a keyword or a URL.
每个字符串不是关键词就是 URL
And we have the keyword followed by the URLs where that keyword appears.
同时还有一个关键词 后面跟着出现该关键词的 URL
This seems nice and simple.
看上去既美观又简单
There's only one list.
只有一个列表而已
There are two real big problems with it.
但是这里有两个大麻烦
The first problem is it's hard to tell the keywords apart from the URLs.
第一个麻烦是 很难区分关键词和 URL
Maybe in this case we would say "well, anything that starts with HTTP is a URL" --
在这个例子里任何以 HTTP 开头的字符串都是 URL
that's a well-formed web link--
我们的 URL 都是格式化后的链接
and anything that doesn't is a keyword.
任何不以 HTTP 开头的都是关键词
But we could have keywords that start with HTTP as well.
但也可能关键词的开头就是 HTTP
and then we couldn't tell which was which.
这么一来 就无法进行区分了
The other really big problem with this representation is
这种表达法的另一个大麻烦就是
it's very hard to loop over the keywords.
关键词的循环遍历非常困难
To find the next keyword, if we start from keyword one,
如果从关键词一开始找下一个关键词
we don't know which position to look at.
从哪个位置开始寻找无从知晓
There are different numbers of links that each keyword might have.
每个关键词可能都有不同的链接数
And we'd have to search through every element
我们不得不对每个元素进行搜索
to try to decide whether the next thing is a URL or the next keyword.
以决定下一个出现的究竟是 URL 还是下一个关键词
So this is not going to work very well.
这种办法行不通
So option one is definitely a bad idea.
所以选项一显然并非良策
So next let's look at option three,
再来看看选项三
which was the other one that I said really would be very difficult.
这个我也说过 非常麻烦
So with option three we have a list
选项三包括一个列表
where each element of the list is itself a list.
列表中的每个元素本身又是一个列表
And the element lists are lists where the first element in the list is a URL.
而元素列表这种列表的第一元素是一个 URL
The second element in the list is a list of keywords.
第二元素是关键词列表
So that would be a list of the keywords that appear at that URL.
URL 中可能会出现的关键词列表
So this has more structure than the first choice.
这个选项比选项一结构繁复
We can tell apart where the URLs are--
我们可以区分 URL 在哪
all the URLs are the first elements of these lists--
因为所有 URL 都是列表的第一个元素
and where the keywords are, which are all contained in the second element of the contained list.
我们也能区分关键词在哪 因为它们都在列表的第二个元素里
The problem with this approach is it's not going to make it easy
这个选项的问题是 我们很难
to look up the pages where a keyword appears.
搜索关键词出现的页面
This almost like having to scan all the pages over again.
要搜索关键词几乎等于重新扫描所有页面
To look for a particular keyword, we've got to look at each entry,
如果要搜索特定关键词 我们要搜索每个元素
look in the second part of that entry,
再搜索元素的第二部分
scan it to see if that keyword appears.
对之进行扫描 确定关键词是否出现
If it does, well then we want this URL in our result.
如果出现了 那么这个 URL 要包含在搜索结果里
If it doesn't, then that URL is not in the result.
如果没有出现 则不出现在搜索结果里
But to find particular keywords, we've got to look through each entry
但找到特定关键词就要搜索每一个元素
and look through all of the keywords in that entry.
和该元素的所有关键词
So this option is not going to work very well.
所以这个选项也行不通
Our goal in making the index was to be able to make look-ups fast
因为我们建立索引的初衷就是实现快速搜索
so we don't have to look through all the content of the pages,
无需浏览这些页面的所有内容
and this representation doesn't solve that problem.
可这个表达法不能解决这一需求
So we have two choices left,
现在 只剩两个选项了
and I said both of these choices could work okay.
我说过 这两个选项都可行
But I think the fourth option is the best one.
但选项四是最佳答案
So let's look at why.
我们来看看原因
So this is option B.
先看选项二
We have a list where each element of the list is a list.
这是一个列表 列表中的每个元素都是一个列表
And the element lists are themselves lists
元素列表自身是包含了关键词的列表
which contain the keyword followed by URLs where that keyword appears.
关键词后面是出现该关键词的URL
This has a big advantage over the first two options.
与前两个选项相较 该选项有个很大的优势
It means it's easier to tell the keywords from the URLs.
即它意味着区分关键词和 URL 更加容易
The keyword is always the first element of the list.
因为关键词始终是列表的第一个元素
And unlike the previous option, it's also easy to go through the keywords.
且与之前选项不同 该选项要浏览关键词很容易
For each list contained, we just need to look at the first element
对于所有包含关键词的列表而言 我们只需检索第一元素
to see if that's the keyword we're looking for.
来确认这是否是我们搜寻的关键词
If not, we go onto the next one.
如果不是 我们就继续搜索
We don't need to look through all the content in all the web pages.
我们不需要浏览所有网页上的全部内容
We just need to look at the first element in these lists to find the keyword we're looking for.
只需浏览列表的第一个元素 来找出关键词
So that's okay.
所以 这个选项可行
The reason that I think option D is better,
我认为选项四更好的原因
is that it makes a better separation between the keywords and the URLs.
则是它对关键词和 URL 进行了更好的区分
So the difference between this and option D
与选项二相比 选项四的不同之处在于
is in option D instead of the inner lists being flat lists
其内部列表不是简单列表
that are the keyword followed by the URLs,
而是跟着 URL 的关键词
the inner list has just two elements.
内部列表只包含了两个元素
It has the keyword followed by a list of URLs.
即关键词 和一列 URL
So that will be another list, and now we have a list of URLs.
这里有另外一个列表 即一列 URL
So this is option D.
这就是选项四
Each element of the main list is a list.
主列表中的每个元素都是一个列表
And it's a list that just contains two elements.
列表只包含两个元素
It contains the keyword--here the keyword "udacity"--
即关键词 - 比如这里的 “udacity”
followed by a list containing all the URLs where that keyword appears.
及其后出现关键词的所有 URL 的列表
The reason I like this better than the second option
比选项二相比我更喜欢这个选项的原因
is that it really makes a clear separation between the keyword and the list of URLs.
是它对关键词和 URL 列表作出了非常清晰的区分
It means if we decide we want to keep track of something else
也就是说 如果我们想对另一些内容
--say we want to keep track of the number of times someone searches for each keyword--
如每个关键词的搜索次数保持跟踪
we could easily do that.
操作会很简便
We could have an extra element here that keeps track of the number of times someone searches for something.
这里可以加一个额外元素 来对搜索次数进行跟踪
With option B, it wouldn't be that clear how to do that.
选项二对此如何操作并不明确
Maybe we could add an extra value in here--we could add a number in here.
也许可以在这里再加个值 在这儿加个数字
We would need to change a lot of code that we already wrote.
我们可能需要对很多已经写好的代码进行修改
Instead of looking for URLs starting from position one,
现在不是从第一个位置开始搜索 URL
we'd have to start from position two now.
而是要从第二个位置位置开始了
Maybe we should put the number at the end to avoid that problem.
或者我们可以将数字加在最后 来避免这一问题
Well then we have the problem of we've got to find where the number is.
但这么一来 我们又得找到这个数字的位置
There are easy ways to find the last element of a list.
有简单的方法来找出列表的最后一个元素
But it's going to make things much more complicated.
但这会使工作更加复杂
And if we start adding more and more things,
而一旦开始插入越来越多的内容
we're going to have a hard time keeping track of everything.
对全部内容进行跟踪就会非常困难
Option D gives us a lot more structure.
选项四提供了更完备的结构
By keeping all the URLs in a list, we can treat that as a list and do things with it
通过将所有 URL 放进一个列表 我们可以将之视为一个列表
much more easily than if it's combined with a keyword.
这样就比将 URL 和关键词绑在一起简单得多了
And we can also do things like add extra elements
我们还可以往里面添加额外的元素
if we want to keep track of the number of times someone searches for that keyword
如果我们希望对关键词搜索次数保持跟踪的话
or any other information we think of later that would be useful to add to our structure.
我们也可添加任何之后有助于我们的结构的其它信息
So that's why I think option D is the best option.
以上就是选项四更优的原因
And deciding on data structures is one of the most important things we do when we build software.
在做软件时 最重要的任务之一就是决定数据结构
If you pick the right data structure,
选对了结果
oftentimes the rest of the code is fairly easy to write.
编写代码的工作变得易如反掌
If you start with the wrong data structure--
选错了
say we started with the structure that was choice A or choice C,
比如这里我们选了选项一或三
well then it's going to be very very difficult,
编写代码则难如登天
sometimes it's going to be impossible, to write the code in a way that performs well.
甚至有时 几乎无法再写出好的代码
So thinking about data structures is one of the most important things we do in computer science.
所以计算机科学最重要的任务之一 就是对数据结构进行思考
We'll see that some more in this course.
本课程中我们还将接触更多
We'll also have following courses that really focus on this question
接下来的课程里 会有专门针对这一问题的内容
of how to design and use data structures well.
会着重介绍如何更好地设计和运用数据